<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.4.1" created="2016-01-12 02:35" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>A Coach Called Life</title>
	<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 02:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://acoachcalledlife.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://acoachcalledlife.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[admin@wordpress.swamyg.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Swamy]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Swamy]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Gopalsamy]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>Growing the resources to transform your life</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/growing-the-resources-to-transform-your-life/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 15:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=63</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The proclivity of life is to keep moving towards vitality. But, as with anything that flows, things can get stuck. This is when we experience the hardships of life. Sometimes the fix is as easy as unplugging the emotional clog through introspection, but other times we might need a full system overhaul. If you are consistently dissatisfied with yourself or if you don’t have a lot of energy or suffer from poor interpersonal friendships and relationships, chances are you might need a system overhaul.

This may seem overwhelming at first, but by applying systematic efforts we might be able to break down old destructive habits and lay the foundation for a stronger self. Imagine a boat stuck in a whirlpool on an otherwise swift flowing river. Without any effort, you are probably going to be spinning around and around until you exhaust yourself. On the other hand, with the right effort applied you will be able to steer yourself out of the vortex. And once out, you start gently floating on the steady current of the river again. Life is exactly the same. There’s a general current pulling us towards excellence, but sometimes we can get sucked into an undertow of depression or general strife. Here in this article I’ll explain how there are six key resources we must develop to help ourselves get back on the gentle stream again.
<h3>Acceptance</h3>
It is first important to be accepting of the present condition that we find ourselves in. When we give into confusion, worrying or panic, it exhausts us. We may feel tired because of the constant struggle we feel fighting the situation we are in. By accepting the present station in life, we save valuable emotional and physical energy which can be directed towards cultivating other internal resources that will eventually enable us to move past our predicament. Worrying begets more worrying, fear births new fears; when you are feeling depressed there is no use feeling sad about how depressed you are. Acceptance short circuits this feedback of anguish. You are left with just your underlying feeling, whether it be depression, fear or being anxious, and from there you can begin to work through it.
<h3>Physical strength</h3>
No matter what stage you are in life you need good physical strength. Without a strong body, your emotional and spiritual progress may suffer and stagger. And fixing this area in your life can be the spark necessary to create that domino effect that ends up in your overall wellness. It is here that you might need some effort to get started. Getting started on fitness can be painful in the beginning, but it is one of the first resources that will contribute to the development of other support systems in life. In my previous article, I showed you how to get started on fitness and turn it into a habit.
<h3>Compassion for the self</h3>
Your emotional well-being has much to do with the relationship you have with yourself and with others. It is easy to get caught in a self-loathing rut or feel afflicted because of your lack of energy and drive, but it’s very important to have a healthy relationship with yourself. If you can’t stand to look at yourself in the mirror, that probably says a lot about your own self-image. Have compassion for yourself. The terrain of life isn’t always a well-paved road; there are definitely rugged contours to move through. By acknowledging that it is not your fault that the roads are bumpy and that you are doing your best to pull through, you can develop some compassion for yourself. It has not always been an easy journey for us. Accept this as part of the human condition.
<h3>Community of friends</h3>
Along with self love, the love and support that you receive from your friends and partners can draw you into balance. Friends and intimate partners can be an integral resource in your transformation. It is never a sign of weakness to ask for help. Learn to make yourself vulnerable and seek to lower your defenses when support comes looking your way.

A community is a social unit of any size that shares the same values. We as social animals long to be part of a group. Without such a resource, it is easy to find yourself alienated even when living in a big city. Creating things together with your peers who share your values and visions of the future can be a highly rewarding experience that can take the worry off of your mind. Sharing an evening meal and a good conversation or dancing all night long with people who share the love for similar music may be a better medicine than any anti-depressant.
<h3>Support &amp; Guidance</h3>
Not all of us are lucky to be part of a supportive community, nor is it always the right kind of guidance that we might be looking for. One of the best ways to navigate the uneven roads of life is to seek out some counseling. The ‘C’ word does have a lot of stigma attached to it. If you find yourself getting defensive when I suggest you seek external help, then it is a good indication that there are parts of yourself that are resistant to change. And it is exactly these parts that might be holding you back.
<h3>A life bigger than yourself</h3>
Sometimes, even after developing a lot of resource for your growth, you will still, from time to time, come face to face with emptiness. Your life may be devoid of unnecessary suffering but it might still feel like there’s something lacking. The absence of a spiritual cause in one’s life is definitely felt, sometimes mild in the background or sometimes loud and clear, looking straight at you. The term “spiritual” here does not explicitly mean in relation to God, it means finding a cause that is bigger than yourself or your ego and dedicating a good portion of your life to it. This can be solving your city’s homelessness epidemic or creating music that brings immense joy to a few thousand folks or taking care of a loved one in need of care. No one cause is bigger than the other. In my life, I’ve felt a sense of higher satisfaction from helping individuals get unstuck in their personal life. What your spiritual cause may look like, you are going to be the one who gets to decide. You will have to do some digging into your inner self. Sit with your emotions, intuitions, and wisdom to find out what values you care about. Do those values bring joy to others? Do they help tear down oppressive structures in our society? Or do they help defend a planet in peril? Figure out something that can be of benefit to at least one person other than you and dedicate your life to it.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>63</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-08-23 15:10:41]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-08-23 15:10:41]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[growing-the-resources-to-transform-your-life]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Kickstarting your fitness journey</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/kickstarting-your-fitness-journey/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=65</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Let’s face it, working out is hard. It is supposed to be. That’s why it makes you stronger. But when you are initially starting on a fitness routine, it is tough to motivate yourself to go to the gym or get out of bed and do 20 pushups. If you’ve never had a consistent habit of physically exerting yourself, then what I just stated could sound excruciating. The mind is quick to come up with hundred different excuses when it knows there’s effort to be applied. But on the other hand, without proper physical fitness you feel weak. And deep down inside, you know you want a healthy and strong life. So why on earth do we experience this conflict?
<h3>Mental resistance</h3>
We are wired to seek out pleasure that requires least effort and that which is most immediate. That’s why it is easy to binge on a pint of ice-cream and Netflix than go for a run. Just as you need some force to move a stationary physical object because of its Newtonian inertia, you will similarly encounter mental resistance when applying any effort. But this resistance is short lived. And like any other resistance, it can be overcome. Initially, this resistance looks monumental and tricks you into believing that you’d be better off just hitting the snooze button. But that is a lie. There are several ways to break it down.
<h3>Change your relationship to fitness</h3>
When fitness and exercise is seen as a chore that needs to be performed in order to avoid ill-health or to keep you from feeling guilty, then finding an excuse is not that hard. A better way would be to think about exercise is as a tool that aids in your overall growth. For example, one of my core values is physical strength. As detailed in <a href="http://acoachcalledlife.com/manifesto/">my manifesto</a>, being physically strong is not only a necessity for my mental well-being but also the foundation on which my advancement rests. Exercise is a prime factor in my growth. I would invite you to change your relationship to exercising from thinking about it as something you do to prevent illness to something that empowers you. Exercise to grow stronger and feel vibrant, not just because your doctor said so or you don’t want to feel like a slob.
<h3>Take Baby steps</h3>
The easiest way to get started is to take a small first step. Suppose you have never been much of a runner and you want to lose weight. You might find it easier to get out the door if you tell yourself that you’d only run for 4 or 5 blocks than telling yourself to run 3 miles on your first run. You may by all means be capable of running for 3 miles, but the resistance associated with such a long distance might make you give up easily before you even begin. Starting small also helps you to gradually build the supportive physical strength and reduce the risk of injuries. The idea here is to gradually increase the intensity as you go along. And when done consistently, a month after you started, you won’t be dreading a 3 mile run or a full 45 minute of weight lifting. You must start with the absolute lowest possible intensity that will make you get up and going without overwhelming you. A 5k run begins with one step. A 225 lbs. squat begins with an empty barbell squat. Start small and take baby steps towards your goal.
<h3>Have a goal and a plan</h3>
Having a goal can help push yourself to take action. Goals can vary from running the next half marathon or 5k to doing ten pushups or twenty pull ups. Goal focused workout can motivate us to get over the initial bump of exercising. When a goal is combined with a good plan, it becomes easier to tackle mental resistance. Going into a workout and figuring out what exercise to perform next can be taxing on your brain. Do not waste your mental energy on this. Know in advance what you are going to be doing in your workout on any given day. It will make you stick to your whole workout and not give up easily. Write your plan out. Keep it simple at first and try stick to it as much as possible. This is paramount in creating a good exercise routine.
<h3>Set up Triggers</h3>
One of the easiest way to initiate a routine is to set up a trigger. For example, this could be as simple as putting on your workout shoes. If you are feeling particularly resistant to working out on a given day, just concern yourself with that one trigger action. Do not care about how cold it is outside to go for a run or how intimidating that squat looks today. Have a narrow focus and put those shoes on. Now what are you going to do? Go back to bed in your Nikes?
<h3>Design your environment and life to reduce excuses</h3>
Find a gym that is closer to your home so your mind is not complaining about how far of a drive it is. Find a trainer, it's highly recommended if you’ve never been able to find the motivation to go to a gym. Pay for 10 sessions upfront. You will go because you wouldn’t want to waste money. If you can’t afford a trainer, join a group class or find a training partner. Use <a href="http://www.meetup.com">meetup.com</a> to find a group or even post it on Facebook asking for your friends to join you. This way you’ll be accountable to an outside agent. Other ways to design an exercise ready environment is to keep everything you need for your workout or run ready and on sight. If you can see it, is not easy to avoid it.

Get enough sleep if you workout in the morning. This means going to bed early a few nights of the week. If you train after work, do not take on anything monumental an hour before your workout. Plan your meetings and schedule them accordingly.
<h3>Be consistent</h3>
The initial few weeks are the hardest just like any other initiative. Figure out a regular schedule and stick to it. Get specific. For example, instead of a vague 3 days a week workout plan, try re-framing it as doing a specific set of exercises on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday at 7 a.m. Once the wheels get moving, a couple of things will happen. You’ll want to see results quickly and things may begin to get boring. First of all, do not worry about results early on. You may find a change in your energy and may feel uplifted. This will make you come back for more. But physical changes will take a few weeks to months. Don’t lose your heart. Your body will take some time to respond to the new stimulus.

If even after a few solid weeks of following a routine you feel it’s hard to stay motivated, then try looking for alternative activities. There are so many options from yoga to rock climbing to rowing to good old weightlifting. But have patience and do not jump into a different activity every week. Consistency is what differentiates someone for whom fitness is part of their lifestyle from people who go to the gym only during the first week of a new year.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>65</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-09-01 15:39:31]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-09-01 15:39:31]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[kickstarting-your-fitness-journey]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The reason you’re not going on second dates</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/second-dates/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 20:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=73</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[How many of us have been in this situation? You go on a first date and think it went well. You come home and text the person about how much fun it was and how’d you’d like to see them again and then you wait. And three days go by and there’s no reply. Frustrated, you try to call or text her again and after a day she texts back saying that she doesn’t think this is going to work out. Or worse, the reply never comes. You’re left wondering what went wrong!
<h3>Failure to attract</h3>
They key reason you are not getting a second date is that you failed to attract the person. Beneath all the conversation and first date rituals lies the core of attraction. When I talk about attraction here, I am talking about turning your date on sexually, presenting yourself with some intrigue and a general vibe of fun. Attraction here doesn’t just mean having good looks; that is definitely going to help you, but in addition you need to be able to arouse interest and turn her on in other ways. Here’s how you do it.
<h3>Relax and be present</h3>
A major complaint women have about first dates is that the man is nervous or unable to be present. People who don’t get second dates are the ones who are approaching the first date as a sequence of steps. Never treat a date as if it’s some kind of flowchart. The best approach would be to let your mind and body relax and focus on what is going on in the present moment. Being in the here and now promotes spontaneity and your conversations and actions can easily turn creative. Being present makes you relax which makes you more present - it’s a feedback loop.

Imagine if you were hanging out with a friend whom you’ve known for a decade - would you be thinking about what to say to her during your conversation? Most likely not. Next time you are on a date and feel really nervous about what to say, imagine that you’ve known her for many years and that she is a good friend. Watch how the conversation transforms.
<h3>Turn off your filters</h3>
Another problem is that you might be too cautious to talk about risky but rewarding topics. There is no use in talking about how it was sunny today or how much it snowed last night. These get boring after the first five minutes. Stop internally monitoring everything you are going to say. Instead, why don’t you speak your mind? I admit that it can be intimidating to open up like that at first, but it can also be utterly rewarding when you are not trying to determine what to talk about and what to avoid.

Also, turning off your usual filters can lead to some interesting conversational territories. My first date conversations sometimes lead into exciting topics, such as recreational drug use, embarrassing sexual experiences, deepest fears, or truth or dares. Hell, I often ask about past awkward first dates on my first date.
<h3>Engage physically</h3>
This is the number one reason why most women feel less attracted to you. You should be comfortable placing a few touches here and there on your date. Ideally, she responds to these by reciprocating or complying with them. It is best to start with a few innocuous touches, like your hand on her thigh or shoulder, for a few seconds and then gradually escalate to more intimate areas. If there is resistance or reluctance, just acknowledge it. That doesn’t mean you verbally apologize. You don’t have to openly ask about whether she thought it was weird or something. Just assume good faith. She will definitely pull back or tell you if she is being bothered by it. This is a precursor to a kiss. And if things are going great and you are connecting with her through your words and your touches, then it is time to go in for a kiss at some point. If you are feeling attracted and connected to the person, just go for it. It can sometimes be as easy as telling them that you feel like kissing them, while holding strong eye contact - and then just waiting to see the reaction. Most of the time there’s silence, but she might show her receptivity with a smile or by meeting your gaze; some will even acknowledge it with a verbal ‘Yes’. And there are times when the girl will say ‘No’. If that is the case, say you are glad you got it off your chest and proceed with something else. Don’t let it upset you - she may not feel ready yet. A lot of advice out there places a lot of importance on the first date kiss. No, your date is not a failure if you didn’t kiss her.
<h3>Give her some space</h3>
When the date is over and you are back home, do not be eager to please her now. Nor try to ask her out immediately on a second date. Wait for the feelings to grow in her. Let her miss you and your texts. If she hasn’t initiated a text or called you after 2-3 days, give her a ring back and tell her you would like to see her sometime the following week. Women liked to be desired but <em>initially</em> they also want to ensure that a man isn’t too available to take them yet. They want someone who they think has other options and has picked them out of those. Your best course of action is to meet other women and casually follow up with her after a few days. Do not be stuck to the phone waiting for her reply.
<h3>What a solid first date looks like</h3>
Every date is different, but a general template of a good first date looks like this. You meet up in a bar and order the first round of drinks. If the girl offers to pay, just tell her she can get the next round. You settle in, ask a few introductory questions and then delve into more inquisitive ones. If you are just asking questions and receiving answers, you are doing it wrong. Be sure to give her ample space to ask you questions and get to know you. This means pulling back sometimes and being ok with a few seconds of silence. Let her do some of the work too. Trust me it’s better this way for both. Sometimes you can share a story or two without her asking a question.

At some point, you casually start to touch her. This will be in the most innocuous places like the thigh or shoulders. Depending on how she reacts, you may move in a bit closer. You can know if the girl is into you by her laughter, how inquisitive she is about you and her responses to those slight touches. After that, it’s time to change venues or take a walk and maybe grab some (cheap) food. If the girl agrees with your suggestion of changing venues or accompanies you on a walk, it is a good sign that she’s liking your company and that the date is going well. Kudos to you. Towards the end, when the date is going well, just go in for a kiss. If there is a strong sexual attraction between you, the kissing can turn into making out. If that happens, ask her if she wants to come home with you for a nightcap. If there is resistance, don’t push too much. If your aim is just to increase your lay-count, it puts too much pressure on you and her. Aim to create a good connection with her so she’s looking forward to see you again. Send her off with a quick intimate hug and a kiss and possibly text her right away about how you enjoyed the time you spent with her. That’s it. Give her the required space for the feelings to grow. If she felt an attraction towards you then there will definitely be a second date.

<strong>P.S.</strong> Sometimes even when things go really well on a first date you might not end up having a second date. She could have just gotten back together with her ex, or decide to take some time off dating. In those cases, if the first date was genuine, she would usually be upfront with her situation. Don’t take this personally.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>73</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-09-13 20:15:40]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-09-13 20:15:40]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[second-dates]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>12</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[sacs longchamp pas chers]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[alberthacone@freenet.de]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://fomministries.org/ljfes/ozpQJmLS/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.29.128.157]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-04 21:07:11]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-04 21:07:11]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[sacs longchamp pas chers, http://fomministries.org/iocli/xjghTEYY/, sac longchamps 
pas cher, http://fomministries.org/kegac/taGOqdLE/, sac 
longchamps pliage pas cher, http://www.jhansitimes.com/desh/rajy/uttar-pradesh/item/1524-embarrassing-up-innocent-25-year-old-raped-by-28-days]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>13</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[longchamp en solde]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[markmuecke@aol.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://saras.co.th/u-en-solde-Vr/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.25.127.221]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-05 19:22:11]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-05 19:22:11]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[longchamp en solde, http://saras.co.th/Longchamp-Lvow7/5-pliage-solde-3y/, sac 
longchamp femme solde, http://saras.co.th/Longchamp-xgh5J/s-en-solde-1d/, sac 
longchamp pas cher solde, http://www.prohaarklinik.at/haartransplantation-vorher-nachher-m-k/]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>14</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[sac longchamp pas cher]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[ewqzsld@gmail.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.creativeactors.co.za/wp-content/Longchamp-ry5vE/n-sac-longchamp-Yu.html#</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[27.155.136.225]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-06 11:28:54]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-06 11:28:54]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[marque sac &agrave; main  sac pliage longchamp pas cher , sac nylon longchamp  sac longchamps planete,
 <a href="http://www.creativeactors.co.za/wp-content/Longchamp-ry5vE/n-sac-longchamp-Yu.html#" title="sac longchamp pas cher" rel="nofollow">sac longchamp pas cher</a>]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>15</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[sacs pliables longchamp soldes]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[reganfawcett@live.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.thegoodlifecellar.com/3-pliables-soldes-1z/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.25.127.223]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-07 02:01:36]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-07 02:01:36]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[sacs pliables longchamp soldes, http://www.thegoodlifecellar.com/Longchamp-xaCKu/x-soldes-pliage-Pi/, sacs en soldes longchamp, http://www.thegoodlifecellar.com/x-soldes-7y/, soldes longchamp, http://typeblind.nl/k2-categories/item/118-uitdagend-lessysteem?start=220]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>16</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[sacs pliage longchamp pas cher]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[kaley_ashe@gmx.net]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.canadiangoosecontrol.com/1-pliage-Ds/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.29.130.200]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-07 02:56:49]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-07 02:56:49]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[sacs pliage longchamp pas cher, http://www.canadiangoosecontrol.com/Longchamp-zfLnO/b-style-7a/, soldes longchamp 
pas cher, http://www.canadiangoosecontrol.com/Longchamp-onRus/w-cuir-Lo/, sac longchamp pas cher soldes, http://nogteff.kiev.ua/index.php/foto/item/34-pedikyur/34-pedikyur?start=0]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>17</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[sac de cours longchamp pas cher]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[ofelialumholtz@web.de]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.thegoodlifecellar.com/Longchamp-m9Bzv/b-de-cours-Ia/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.25.126.147]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-10 08:17:33]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-10 08:17:33]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[sac de cours longchamp pas cher,longchamp neo noir,longchamp pliage 
toile prix,http://www.bjweekly.com/archives/2601137.html]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>18</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[sac besace longchamp soldes]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[erikgyles@gmail.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://saras.co.th/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.25.126.147]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-10 20:05:50]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-10 20:05:50]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[sac besace longchamp soldes,http://saras.co.th/Longchamp-falso/e-sac-longchamp-F5/,sac longchamp femme bandoulière,sac cuir 
femme longchamp,http://loreephotography.com/calgary-photographers-fish-creek-park/,http://prestigefleethire.com/index.php/fleet-offering/24-hours-service-and-care?start=70,http://wecanmake.net/index.php/blog/26-lorem-ipsum-is-simply-dummy?start=1250]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>19</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[sacoche longchamp homme pas cher]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[krista.hastings@zoho.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://beautysphere.com.au/Longchamp-xj7wB-x-homme-Wu.aspx</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.25.126.147]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-10 21:05:52]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-10 21:05:52]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[sacoche longchamp homme pas cher,http://beautysphere.com.au/Longchamp-1Oe5J-c-femme-Km.aspx,sacoche longchamp homme prix,sac longchamp noir pas cher,http://www.starhousecollective.com/licensing/item/69-aqua-alta/69-aqua-alta?long=1&amp;button=%B2%E9%D1%AF&amp;start=70,http://pipnee3.com/garcinia_fast3590,http://divatalkkir.com/diva-s-monthly-wisdom/birthdays/item/22-divatalk-september-anniversaries]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>20</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[solde sac a main longchamp]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[mirtaselph@gmail.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.brisbanepropertyadvisers.com/Longchamp-5rNrM-e-solde-a-main-Ls.html</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.25.126.147]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-10 22:09:02]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-10 22:09:02]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[solde sac a main longchamp,http://www.brisbanepropertyadvisers.com/Longchamp-wYb37-k-a-main-homme-Cq.html,malette longchamp homme,
sac longchamp homme cuir,http://ipppp.ru/index.php/blog/blog-grid-style/item/20-lorem-ipsum-dolor-sit?limitstart=0,http://moblevaliasr.ir/index.php/component/k2/item/12-nam-lacinia-velit-et-enim-aliquam,http://www.plazapalmardearamara.com/k2-demo-1/item/435-laboratorio-de-patologia-clinica-palmar-de-aramara.html]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>21</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[porte monnaie longchamp pliage]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[barneymatthaei@gmail.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.mariotonjones.com/Longchamp-5aFke/b-porte-monnaie-pliage-Vk/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.25.126.147]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-10 22:55:25]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-10 22:55:25]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[porte monnaie longchamp pliage,http://www.mariotonjones.com/Longchamp-ZD7p9/n-pliage-homme-Gc/,sac de voyage boxford 
longchamp,sac longchamp pliage noir,http://alepadesign.ru/index.php/k2-about/item/372-css3-integration/372-css3-integration,http://www.datumcorporation.com/blog/post/the-benefits-of-a-cio,http://www.datumcorporation.com/blog/post/the-benefits-of-a-cio]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>22</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Longchamp Pas Chers]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[martinastonor@vegemail.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.gospellighthouse.ca/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[117.25.126.147]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-01-11 00:08:37]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-01-11 00:08:37]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[http://tsvo-basketball.de/search/node/http%3A/%252Fwww.mariotonjones.com/Longchamp-WcmC1/t-bleu-marine-Mg/ http://ktx.co.ke/index.php/porfolio/item/42-portfolio-content-7 http://nexsoftware.net/-7-/index.php?topic=56914.0 http://forum.parole-en-arradon.net/viewtopic.php?pid=111289 http://www.pairidaeza.net/forums/index.php?topic=266201.0 http://emrl.gntech.ac.kr/?document_srl=810049 http://www.takshilaonline.com/forum/viewtopic.php?pid=423327 http://internetbizsecrets.com/fluxbbforum/viewtopic.php?pid=980266 ,http://radiomanding.com/afrique-de-l-ouest/item/1589-un-dfil-du-14-juillet-sous-le-signe-de-lamiti-franco-malienne.html,http://unitedgroup.com.pk/sulzer-shuttle-less-looms/sulzer-p7100-b330-n1-ep-e10-d1-looms.html]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>What traveling alone can bring into your life</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/travel-alone/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 05:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=75</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[A lot of people love to travel, but usually with a group of friends. Ask them if they have ever traveled alone and you are most likely to get a quizzical look back. "Why would I do that?" some might ask. What most people don't realize is that traveling alone can be the single most beneficial act one can do to help oneself grow. But if the mere thought of being with yourself far away from home disturbs you, then read on to see what it can deliver.
<h3>Become better at organizing</h3>
Ideally, when you travel with a group, the organizing and planning are split equally amongst the people of the group. This is usually not the case, a few end up handling way more than their share while the rest don't get involved at all. If you are at either end of the spectrum then traveling alone balances you out. If you are someone who piles everything on yourself, then by taking a solo sojourn you ensure that you are only in charge of yourself. On the other hand, if you have never taken an initiative to plan a trip, then forcing yourself to travel alone will enable you to expand your planning abilities. Even though you initially thought you would never be able to accomplish anything, you'll quickly learn about your abilities to put a trip together. If planning a trip by yourself makes you really nervous and it's something you have never done before, I'd suggest starting out with a short weekend trip. Once you gain the confidence in yourself you'll find it easier to pack for longer trips and eventually find a way to get the most out of your travel with minimal packing and planning.
<h3>Overcome self-doubt</h3>
When former president of the US, Teddy Roosevelt, suffered a major defeat in the 1912 election, he packed his bags and went to South America to map one of the most dangerous rivers in Brazil: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0767913736/">the river of doubt</a>. President Roosevelt has earned a special place in history by undertaking the most arduous of journeys whenever he felt tested by crippling doubt and defeat. You don't have to put yourself through any such perilous struggle to prove something to yourself, but it can be such a boost to your confidence when you come back home from a two-week vacation all by yourself. Even during your travel, you will feel poise in your spirit that often leaves you wondering where the fear was coming from and why you hadn't done this before. The confidence gained by solitary travel can seep into other areas in your life which are governed by self-doubt and fear. Suddenly you don't hesitate to walk up to a person to ask them out for drinks or it isn't such a big deal to finally join that dance class you know you have always wanted to try.
<h3>Invite spontaneity</h3>
Spontaneity is the action that occurs as a result of an inner impulse or inclination and often without premeditation. Spontaneity is also an alias for magic. Saying yes to a situation and thereby inviting spontaneity into your existence becomes easier when traveling alone. Local people who find you curious will welcome you inside their homes. You might meet someone and decide to change all your travel plans at once. There are no worries of hurting anyone or being hurt by being this flexible. You can choose to eat where you want, what you want and when you want. Being spontaneous means grappling with the current situation without a lot of thinking or prior planning. Some might ask whether this is a good thing. A voice inside of you would even question, "Won't being spontaneous lead me to dangerous places or make me do things that I might regret later?" That is fear talking, and as long we listen to that part of our brain we will only be limited to doing things that it deems to be safe. We will only visit places that are within the control and confines of fear. That would mean limiting the flow of your life. Life itself is spontaneous, dynamic and in a state of flux. Recognizing this and saying yes to the many opportunities presented while you are traveling trains you to be open and yielding in your normal everyday mode.
<h3>New friends and lovers</h3>
This is by far one of the best reasons for me to travel by myself. Vagabonding alone presents several chances to meet new people and make good friends. The possibility of finding an attractive fellow traveler, spending time connecting with them and ending up on a romantic adventure is very real. Traveling with a group often restricts you to people you know. Why would you go out of your way to talk to someone when you can just sit around and talk to your friends? There is definitely fun in going to new places with close friends, but if that is all you are doing then you are not stepping out of your comfort zone. There is a whole world of other people out there, people who can bring new perspectives in your life. They might introduce you to a new type of music or tell you stories of places unheard of. Maybe you'll be inspired to change something in yourself by the people who don't live the same way as you do. It takes a certain bit of courage to approach an unfamiliar person, but this is precisely what you'll be forced to do when you are traveling alone. You'll be ejected out of your seat of comfort to talk to someone either by necessity, like asking for directions, or out of boredom. This is a skill which you can bring back when you enter your familiar world again. Though the connections that are formed when traveling can sometimes only be transient, they have the potential to be rich and deep. People tend to open up more when they are in a new and unfamiliar setting.
<h3>An opportunity to get to know ourselves</h3>
<blockquote><em>I think one travels more usefully when they travel alone, because they reflect more.</em> - Thomas Jefferson</blockquote>
Society has us thinking that being alone equals being a loser. Lana Del Rey famously echoes this sentiment in her lines,<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cE6wxDqdOV0"> "They say that the world was built for two; Only worth living if somebody is loving you." </a>This is perhaps the biggest fear that prevents people from solo travel. Some of us are afraid of being alone with ourselves and our thoughts. That fear will always resonate with us until the time we cross over to the other side and see that being alone is not a frightening place to be. In fact, it can be just as enriching as time spent in the company of kindred spirits.

[caption id="attachment_80" align="aligncenter" width="704"]<a href="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/meisterwerke_caspar_david_friedrich_wanderer_ueber_dem_nebelmeer_a.jpg"><img class="wp-image-80 size-full" src="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/meisterwerke_caspar_david_friedrich_wanderer_ueber_dem_nebelmeer_a.jpg" alt="" width="704" height="396" /></a> <em>Wanderer above the sea of fog by Romantic painter Caspar David Friedrich. You could be one too.</em>[/caption]

Nowadays we rarely get any time to reflect on our inner lives. We are consumed by the time we spend on our devices and mundane interactions. We watch TV, copiously use social media and hang out with people way more than we need to. By traveling alone, we get to hang out with someone most dear to us: ourselves. When was the last time you dug into your feelings? Do you remember hearing your own deepest thoughts? Have you ever felt like you knew your place in the cosmos? When sitting by yourself, the sight of a great ocean or a roaring mountain can be quite the source of profound introspection. A lot of romantic landscape paintings use the device of a lonely person embedded in the most awesome setting to drive home the point of quiet contemplation that is readily available for the solitary wanderer. When external noise is reduced, when other people are absent to distract us and when we are in silent rumination, there is a clear moment of awareness about our inner selves. Moments like that bring us closer to our deeper longings and put us in touch with the emotions that are beneath the level of everyday perception. We could go on with our lives without paying close attention to our inner disturbances, but to become whole we have to integrate those thoughts and feelings that we have chosen to consciously or unconsciously ignore.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>75</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-09-24 05:20:55]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-09-24 05:20:55]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[travel-alone]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>11</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[seo plugin]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[jpbkmivl@gmail.com]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.SeoOptimizedRankings.com/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[107.172.7.77]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2015-12-29 23:34:26]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-12-29 23:34:26]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hello Web Admin, I noticed that your On-Page SEO is is missing a few factors, for one you do not use all three H tags in your post, also I notice that you are not using bold or italics properly in your SEO optimization. On-Page SEO means more now than ever since the new Google update: Panda. No longer are backlinks and simply pinging or sending out a RSS feed the key to getting Google PageRank or Alexa Rankings, You now NEED On-Page SEO. So what is good On-Page SEO?First your keyword must appear in the title.Then it must appear in the URL.You have to optimize your keyword and make sure that it has a nice keyword density of 3-5% in your article with relevant LSI (Latent Semantic Indexing). Then you should spread all H1,H2,H3 tags in your article.Your Keyword should appear in your first paragraph and in the last sentence of the page. You should have relevant usage of Bold and italics of your keyword.There should be one internal link to a page on your blog and you should have one image with an alt tag that has your keyword....wait there's even more Now what if i told you there was a simple Wordpress plugin that does all the On-Page SEO, and automatically for you? That's right AUTOMATICALLY, just watch this 4minute video for more information at. <a href="http://www.SeoOptimizedRankings.com" rel="nofollow">Seo Plugin</a>]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[0]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>It&#039;s time to listen to your anxiety</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/listen-to-anxiety/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 03:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=98</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[It's Monday morning. You wake up to find yourself feeling dreadful again. What happened? It was not a particularly bad weekend; there was nothing stressful about the past few days, but there it is - that Monday morning anxiety. It feels very unpleasant to wake up like this. Our first instinct is to try everything in our heads to rid ourselves of this dread. You might succeed in numbing out the feeling briefly, but that doesn't last long. Anxiety always strikes back. Since you haven't been able to free yourself from the grip of your distress, what if, instead of chasing it away every time your chest constricts, you turned around, met your anxiety eye to eye and listened to what it had to say?

It is my firm belief that anxiety arises out of an existential crisis. Now, what does that mean? To put it simply, you may be experiencing difficulties in certain key areas of your life and the anxiety may be a sign that is pointing to this underlying problem. This conclusion might sound really obvious. "Of course!", you would say, "My life is difficult because I've been struggling with this anxiety for years". It is almost easy to conclude that our lives are not in line because of our underlying everyday struggle with anxiety, but it is also very possible that the anxiety is the result of an unbalanced life.

Ask yourself some of these questions:
<ul>
	<li>What do I constantly worry about besides my anxiety?</li>
	<li>Is my chosen line of work really the right path for me?</li>
	<li>Are my intimate relationships in the best shape possible?</li>
	<li>Have I come to terms with the limitations of life or am I struggling hard to change the unchangeable?</li>
	<li>Am I still troubled by unhealed wounds from my past?</li>
</ul>
Chances are, there are areas of your life that require a closer look. Even if your anxiety were to disappear suddenly tomorrow, some of your existential problems would still persist. Sure, you may briefly feel a relief and that may cause you to, for example, continue the job that you've never liked, but it won't be long before you start to feel some sort of deep, underlying, unpleasant feeling again.

Scott Stossel in his <a href="http://www.amazon.com/My-Age-Anxiety-Dread-Search/dp/0307269876" target="_blank">epic tome about anxiety</a> illustrates this relationship between our lives and our anxiety. He writes:
<blockquote>Anxiety, as Dr. Barry Wolfe says, is a signal that the usual defenses against unbearably painful views of the self are failing. Rather than confronting the reality that your marriage is failing, or that your career has not panned out, or that you are declining into geriatric decrepitude, or that you are going to die — hard existential truths to reckon with — your mind sometimes instead produces distracting and defensive anxiety symptoms, transmuting psychic distress into panic attacks or free-floating general anxiety or developing phobias onto which you project your inner turmoil.</blockquote>
Ask yourself, what areas don't feel right in your life right now? Make sure that the problems you unravel exist in the present. Don't waste your time with problems of the past that make no sense currently, though it is possible that traumatic events from the past that were not resolved or healed have the potential to show up in the present and they are definitely to be counted. It is important to bring these psychic distresses into your field of awareness. Most often these may be events or circumstances that we do not want to wrestle with. We may be trying to avoid confronting certain hard truths about us and our lives. For instance, it is very common for people to not acknowledge that their marriage is failing because of the consequences it can have for them and their children. Stossel talks about a college sophomore who trained all his life to become a concert pianist. He was beset with panic attacks when his professors told him that he wasn’t talented enough to realize his dream.

However once a person is able to recognize their underlying issue and come to terms with the truth behind them, their anxiety symptoms go away.
<blockquote>Interestingly, a number of recent studies have found that at the moment an anxious patient begins to reckon consciously with a previously hidden psychic conflict, lifting it from the murk of the unconscious into the light of awareness, a slew of physiological measurements change markedly: blood pressure and heart rate drop, skin conductance decreases, levels of stress hormones in the blood decline. Chronic physical symptoms—backaches, stomachaches, headaches—often dissipate spontaneously as emotional troubles that had previously been “somaticized,” or converted into physical symptoms, get brought into conscious awareness.</blockquote>
It is even possible to be aware of your problem, but you might be trying to circumvent the core issue by working around it. You might not want to live in a bustling metropolis but instead yearn to move to the countryside. Since that may come at the risk of losing your job, you might desperately try to bring in peace and quietude through daily activities such as calming guided meditations or a lunch-time stroll through a small park. Nevertheless, you may feel anxious whenever your urban tranquility is disturbed by the unavoidable dissonant rhythms of city life. I get it, it is not easy to throw away a life you have tried to build for several years, but if this is not where a big part of yourself wants to be then frantically trying to bargain with the unworkable areas of your life is going to be harder in the long run.

People readily buy into the notion that they may have a biological propensity towards anxiety, but find it hard to admit that their anxiety could be a result of not coming to terms with their reality. It is relatively easy to blame genetics and continue to be tortured by panic attacks than to make the necessary change in one's life. I'm not saying that there's no biological basis for anxiety, but it is unwise to entirely blame your genes without any introspection about the root of your worries. Once you admit these truths to yourself and make the required changes in your life, you'll start to feel lighter and there might not be a need for this underlying anxiety.

On some occasions, it might be very easy to put a finger on the source of the distress and imbalance in our being. Other times, our tired mind has trouble figuring out the root of our existential challenges. Life would be simple if our minds had the ability to easily tune into our feelings (both pleasant and unpleasant) and interpret what's behind them, but in the midst of strong emotions the mind often cannot think straight. It is not uncommon to associate benign activities such as going out for a walk to be the cause of dreadful feelings. We avoid talking to people or going out because we can't handle the anguish of being with someone and our anxiety at the same time. The result is that we lose out on life. Instead of making unsound associations in figuring out the cause of our anxiety, let's try to understand the existential aspects of our lives and see if we can find out whether anything is out of alignment.

You can make a great start by listening to your anxiety and seeing it as a signal to issues that demand your attention and awareness. If, on the other hand, you are struggling to figure out where the instability in your life is coming from, find someone to <a href="http://acoachcalledlife.com/workwithme/">work with your anxiety</a>. When you are in the cycle of worry and feeling anxious, bringing some clarity through external help may be just what is needed. Talk to that person, not just about your anxiety but also about other issues that may be bothering you. It might be easier for a professional to make the connection between the various problematic areas in your life and their manifestations as anxiety or any other mental illnesses. With the right guidance and support and by implementing the necessary changes in your life, you will begin to feel the loosening grip of anxiety over time.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>98</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-10-09 03:39:38]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-10-09 03:39:38]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[listen-to-anxiety]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Stranger in a Strange Land: My Depersonalization Story</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/my-depersonalization-story/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 06:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=103</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>"I find myself regarding existence as though from beyond the tomb, from another world; all is strange to me; I am, as it were, outside my own body and individuality; I am depersonalized, detached, cut adrift. Is this madness?... No."  </em>

<em>  - </em>Henri-Frédéric Amiel

Depersonalization (DP) is painful to live with. It scares you, exhausts you, torments you, and then teases by giving you a little break, only to take tackle you again when you least expect it. I developed DP over four years ago over a period of two months that just completely took me by surprise. The carpet was suddenly pulled out from under me and I found myself standing on molten lava. I felt completely disconnected from the reality which I used to take for granted. The sheer terror of looking in the mirror and feeling completely alien to myself can never be serialized into words. What made it more painful was that I wasn’t able to share how I was feeling with my close friends and family because I felt like they would not understand. The feeling is very hard to describe and also very hard for people to comprehend. It’s like telling someone what taking a tab of LSD is like; they are not going to get it unless they’ve dropped acid before. Often depersonalization comes bundled with derealization (DR), as if it were some kind of super-saver pack of dread. A buy one, get one offer that you never wanted in the first place. I will refer to the condition as DP/DR since they almost always cohabitate with one another.

DP/DR robs you of your confidence to feel like yourself. If you are walking around, watching your life like a movie inside your head, experiencing everything in the third person, then how can you respond normally to people? There were so many times I felt like an alien that had just landed on this dreadful planet called Earth. Now, in my mind I <em>knew</em> that this was not true, but I <em>felt</em> everything was different than how it used to be. I longed for the day I would be normal again. I yearned to wake up one day to find this feeling gone and feel reintegrated into reality. The fearful thoughts would subside once in a while, like when the tide goes out, only to be replaced with a mild sadness and anguish about my predicament. The uncertainty of how long I would have to endure this was taking a toll on me. I had no answer. Nevertheless, I was fully functional on the outside. I still showed up to work, hung out with friends, practiced with my band every week, and went on dates, even though I felt like there was a thin veil between myself and the rest of the world. At times, when the DP/DR was in full swing, trying to hide my discomfort was so taxing to me. I wasn’t ashamed of feeling this way, I just thought people would not be able to understand me. It felt like being high on marijuana to an uncomfortable level, and just being there in that place for years.

My experiences included the following:
<ul>
	<li>A general feeling of disconnect from reality.</li>
	<li>Often looking at my hands and not feeling like they were my own.</li>
	<li>Watching my reflection in the mirror and unable to feel that it was me.</li>
	<li>When I spoke, I’d feel as though the words were not mine. They felt alien, even though on the outside I was very coherent.</li>
	<li>My memories seemed so vague. I remembered old memories and could form new ones, but the memories had a dream-like quality to them.</li>
	<li>Extreme sensitivity to caffeine, alcohol and other stimulants.</li>
	<li>Being excessively concerned with existential questions like, “Why am I here? How do I exist? Is existence real or is it a dream? Am I dead and in some kind of purgatorial world?”</li>
	<li>Having a racing mind that was filled with thoughts which were very nonsensical in nature. I had trouble concentrating.</li>
	<li>Experiencing panic when the intensity of DP/DR increased. The panic and DP/DR would feed off each other.</li>
	<li>Feeling a general sense of doom and dread about losing my sanity.</li>
	<li>Experiencing somatic symptoms like a blunt pressure on my forehead, general dizziness, weightlessness in my hands and legs, tightness in my chest.</li>
	<li>Feeling disoriented, as if I were walking upside down or sideways.</li>
</ul>
There were other strange experiences that I felt but these were the most pronounced.
<h3>The Path Towards Recovery</h3>
Fortunately, I came to understand early on that my DP/DR was just an offshoot of anxiety. It is something that develops when the stresses in one’s life become greater than the resources that are available to cope with them. Reading other people’s recovery stories on the internet filled me with hope. I was still unaware of the cause of my anxiety but I was willing to accept it for what it was. <strong>Acceptance is the key towards recovery</strong>. This was an insight that I gained and for some reason it resonated deeply with me. I was really resistant to the idea of taking medication for my condition. The strongest reason being that there was no medication that had been invented yet specifically for DP/DR. Other reasons that prevented me from reaching for medication included the possible side effects of the drugs, and not wanting to be dependent on an external resource to manage my illness. However, I am not completely opposed to people taking medication to manage their anxiety.

As I learned to accept my anxiety, I still felt depersonalized, but it wasn’t scary anymore. I understood that your perception changes when there is too much adrenaline in your body. When the mind is stressed out, it disassociates to protect itself. Evolutionarily speaking, it is better to go through life feeling detached than to be completely broken down by multiple stressors. Because of my understanding, I knew that there was no need to be afraid of how I was feeling. My DP/DR went from being really scary to just very unpleasant.

I journaled about my fears, thoughts, physical sensations, and feelings. Instead of letting these fears hang around in my mind, I gave them a voice and channeled them into my journal entries. When things were lurking inside my head they seemed really dreadful, but when I put them into words they seemed to lose their intensity. It helped me to defuse their power. The other major benefit of journaling was that whenever I had a setback, I’d go back and read about the days when I felt better. This instantly calmed me down. When you are in the throes of anxiety or in the full swing of DP/DR, you tend to forget that you have been there before and have come out of it. You need a reminder that what you are experiencing is only temporary unpleasantness.

I was well aware that there would be setbacks: it’s how this recovery process works. Weeks would go by without any particular incidents, and then suddenly one morning I’d wake up feeling anxious for the next few days. One has to accept this cycle of progress. However, with every setback and eventual advancement, I grew confident in the knowledge that what I was experiencing was not going to kill me or drive me insane. I had been through it many times before and had gotten out unharmed every time.

Another realization that helped me move towards recovery was when I realized that it was a waste of precious resources to worry excessively about one’s condition, even in those dark moments. It is exactly because of this unnecessary worrying that the stress hormones are elevated, which results in more depersonalization. This cycle has to be broken. The best place to start is to realize that worrying works against you. Start there and nip it in the bud. Realize that you are not in harm’s way: you are simply experiencing a weird protective mechanism of your mind. Once I found solace in this fact, I could relax and let my guard down. There was no need for me to be always vigilant against anxiety. When I accepted my fear, the fear lost its meaning. I still felt the fear and would be out of touch with reality for a while, but it did not bother me as much as it did before.

The recovery process takes time. The mileage may vary for every individual. Acceptance is a practice that requires long-term commitment. I eventually started taking the backseat to let my body and mind heal themselves. When you have a broken bone, all you can do is set it in place, put a cast around it, and give it time. The body will gradually grow the bone back to its original setting. Similarly, I accepted the depersonalization, the fear, and the unpleasantness, and got on with my life. I did what I really cared about and left the rest up to the automatic healing mechanisms of the mind and the body. I gave myself permission to feel whatever I was feeling at that moment. My body and mind were doing the best they could and I understood that if I got out the of way, healing would occur automatically.

Along with acceptance, I felt action was also necessary. Action not in combating the DP/DR, but in other areas of my life that demanded some attention. I discovered that exercising not only made me stronger but also helped in warding off the anxiety. By incorporating weight lifting and rock climbing into my fitness routines, it was incredibly refreshing for me to stay in the present moment as opposed to being lost in unwanted rumination about what was going on inside of me.

I had found that caffeine greatly increased my anxiety. As I had not been much of a coffee drinker, I easily switched to decaf. Also, cutting down on drinking not only staved off the anxiety, it also made me healthier. Even though I have a medical marijuana card, I had to cut down and, on occasions, completely stop using marijuana for recreational use.

And finally, I got a lot of help and support when I started seeing a therapist. The first therapist I found did not have a sufficient understanding of dissociative conditions like DP/DR, but eventually I ended up finding someone who had firsthand experience of the phenomenon. That was a big relief to me, to be able to talk to someone who understood what I was going through and to see that this person had come through to the other side.

These days, I do feel depersonalized on a few occasions, and sometimes it can be for days at a stretch, but it does not startle me like it used to. I am able to live with this feeling and not be overwhelmingly consumed in trying to rid myself of it. It has even enabled me to experience reality at a unique level, one that I’d not be privy to if I did not have this condition.
<h3>Note to Sufferers</h3>
I understand how you are feeling right now. I’ve been there before. I want to tell you that you are going to be fine. Trust me, even though right now you might be on the edge of your being, feeling nervous and in a state of confusion, know that this will all pass over time. You are not going to lose your mind, you are not going insane, you are not going to die, you are not going to harm yourself or others. That is just your mind talking. This is what I wanted to hear when I was in the middle of the DP/DR storm, and I hope it brings comfort to you when you read it.

When you are in a state of extreme stress and panic, your cognition (the process of thinking) changes. Once the stress levels are back to normal, your thoughts will be too. You will have your personality back. In fact, you will emerge from this stronger than you were before. Accept these feelings without trying to resist them. You don’t have to do anything special to accept something: you just have to do nothing. That probably goes against the grain of what you are thinking right now. You may feel the need to battle this DP/DR demon, or put up a fight to get rid of your anxiety, but those efforts are always in vain. You need to understand that you are having a normal reaction to the high level of stress that you are experiencing in your life. DP/DR is serving as a protective layer against the incredible stress you are feeling, some of which can arise out of the depersonalization itself. It is not a perfect mechanism, but it is how our brains are wired.

Stop consuming caffeine and see how you feel. Same with other stimulants such as nicotine and herbs like ginseng. Cut down on your alcohol consumption. If you use recreational drugs, experiment with not taking them for a few weeks and notice if you feel any different. Do not use any psychedelics without the support of a well trusted companion. If possible, avoid them until you start feeling better.

Use the internet to find a professional who specializes in dissociative disorders; talk to them and ask them if they understand what you are going through. I also offer <a href="http://acoachcalledlife.com/workwithme/">coaching and support over Skype/phone or in-person</a> for sufferers to get through these difficulties in their life. Though there is helpful information on several forums on the internet, you have to steer clear of the resounding hopeless sentiment that can sometimes exist in these places. As Alan Watts once said, “When you get the message, hang up the phone.” You have to disconnect from the practice of constantly searching and reading up on DP/DR. That can exhaust your already tired mind. You need to engage with life, rather than just your computer. A walk in the park fosters more healing than sedentary time in front of a screen.

Even now, on some days my DP/DR can be very strong, lifting me from the calm present moment to a state of surreal confusion. Nevertheless, I know that these feelings don’t last very long. They always dissipate like the sweat on your skin. You can either allow these feelings and let them come and go as they wish, eventually leading to their extinction, or you can hold on to them, worry about them, and prolong their stay.

Connect with the world and the people around you even though it is overwhelming at times. Start small and progress gradually at a pace that you find comfortable. Let me reiterate that there’s nothing wrong with you and that you are not going crazy, however bleak the situation looks. Don’t waste valuable energy trying to hide it from others. I understand that people may not be able to comprehend what you are going through, but that doesn’t mean they can’t empathize with your suffering. You’ll find that once you open up to your loved ones, the people you are close to, it becomes easier for you to be in the same room with your feelings and other people. Just as you wouldn’t try to hide a fractured bone from your friends and partners, don’t stress yourself out by concealing the way you feel. And no, these feelings do not make you a weaker person.

I hope that by sharing my story I have instilled some hope in you. In my early struggle with DP/DR I wanted assurance that I was going to be all right. That is what I want you, the reader, to take away from this article. You are going to be fine. You will get through this.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>103</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-10-19 06:54:31]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-10-19 06:54:31]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[my-depersonalization-story]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Break Down Your Barriers to Love</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/barriers-to-love/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 23:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=114</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Who doesn't want to be in love? Who doesn't want to love and be loved? Even someone who says they don't care for love is only saying it out of past hurts. The truth is, love is our birthright. We all desire to give and receive it. Though love is our essential nature as spiritual beings, on a human level it is not very readily available because of our apparent separation from one another. But, even within the confines of our human condition, it is still very possible to find the love that we deeply crave if we can identify the barriers that we have put in place to stop its flow.

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-116 size-full" src="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/rumi_quote_blog_7.jpg" alt="Seek the barriers to love" width="851" height="315" />

Rumi, the wise 13th-century Sufi mystic, informs us that love is all around us, waiting to get into our lives if only we could recognize the restrictions we have placed against it. Such barriers could be conscious or unconscious, physical or emotional. They could be a result of a hurtful past or a hedge against a fearful future. I strongly believe the love that Rumi talks about is an all-encompassing love that is comprised of the love for oneself, the love for others and love as the fabric of the universe itself. Here, I mainly want to focus on self-love and interpersonal love.
<h3>Loving yourself</h3>
All forms of love start with self-love. By accepting yourself and being at peace within, you can become accepting of others. It also is the most difficult place to start for a lot of people. There is a direct relationship between the love that you received when you were young and the self-love you possess today. Our parents were supposed to be the bastion of unconditional love from whom we were to model our kinship with ourselves. However, this might not have been the case for you. How could you know what love is if you weren’t cherished as a child? On the other hand, it still is possible for people to not accept themselves despite the support and nurture they received from their parents. Self-love can be very paradoxical.

The good news is self-love can be cultivated. It may not be easy, but with systematic effort one can learn to accept oneself, see their inherent worth, and eventually learn to cherish and love their own existence. This is not an invitation to be narcissistic. There's a difference between a healthy amount of self-love and feelings of extreme pride and conceit. It is tempting to cling to either pole of the self-love spectrum. Some either totally hate themselves while others are too blinded by their own arrogance to admit any faults. But there is always a healthy medium where one admits to their errors but with forgiveness. At the same time, one can recognize their own self-worth and the validity of their existence but no more than the person next to them.

There are two main ways to cultivate self-love, and they are not mutually exclusive. In fact, going down one path eventually leads you to the mouth of the other. First is the path of self-acceptance. Being human, we come in different flavors and with different quirks. Our abilities and limitations vary from person to person. Accepting our own uniqueness with all of our perceived flaws is a good place to start. The act of self-acceptance begins with accepting all the thoughts about ourselves. The trick is to accept them but not believe in all of them. The idea here is to see all the judgments and conclusions in one's head as mere thoughts appearing in a space of awareness. "Nobody will ever love me" or "I am worthless and incapable of finding love" are simply ideas that occupy our minds at a given point in time. By believing in these thoughts, we are reinforcing this pattern of thinking over and over again. Realize that these are just the stories that you tell yourself. They seem to be true because we are familiar with them, but you probably lack any valid reasoning to support them. Accept these thoughts, but give no credence to them. Even if you have done something in the past that has warranted you to carry these burdensome thoughts with you now, it does you no good to be bogged down by a set of neurons firing together to the same old beat. Change your internal rhythm. The more we accept our thoughts (while not believing them), the less troublesome they become and, hence, they gradually weaken and lose their intensity.

To invite love into your life, you must be willing to understand that you are worthy of love, regardless of what your mind keeps telling you. You may be conditioned by years and years of self-harming patterns of thinking. As a child of this vast and loving universe, know that it is your birthright to be loved. Once you understand that you are held by a universal force of love that has made possible the very conditions of your existence, it becomes easier to accept yourself.

The second path is that of action to change. By changing our external appearance, we can foster internal change. This internal change will loop back, making you feel more confident about your self-image. Start with your physical body. If you feel weak and tired most of the time, breath in some energy by <a href="http://acoachcalledlife.com/kickstarting-your-fitness-journey/">starting a regimented fitness program</a>. If you've always struggled with weight issues, get a handle on your nutrition and watch yourself transform week after week. It is definitely not an easy task. But if you start small and stay consistent, you are bound to see changes over time. As you begin to change physically, look for ways to enhance your new appearance. Donate your old clothes to the nearest Goodwill, and shop for better-fitting and more stylish clothing. You'll definitely remember the first time you look in the mirror and find a better-dressed, more stylish version of yourself. Apart from your appearance, take time to enhance your mental abilities. Learn a new language or a new skill. Maybe it's time you invested in those guitar lessons. Take some time off, and go on a retreat. Foster changes that make you feel good about yourself and the self-love will follow automatically.

Self-love is hard work, at least initially. There will always be ups and down. It's a commitment we are making to someone most dear to us—ourselves. It's a promise not to judge ourselves harshly, to give ourselves more room for errors, to let ourselves fail, and to be strong yet tender in our hearts. Being critical hasn't worked that well for most of us. Why not do the opposite and see where it takes us?

It is not uncommon to have a higher regard for ourselves when our need for love is provided by someone else. Our own self-love can increase with the affection that we receive from another. One must be careful not to tie our entire self-worth or self-love to an external source. It is great if someone can maximize the joy we feel for ourselves. However, the source of our self-love should not be completely bequeathed into the hands of another; it must remain within us.
<h3>Loving another</h3>
The journey to loving others also starts within—when we are able to identify the internal obstacles we have placed between ourselves and the external world. Because of past hurts, we erect barriers to intimacy. We get impatient with others because they are not the way we expect them to be in a given moment. We push them away. We are scared of closeness. We are afraid of rejection. Yet, deep down we yearn for the intimacy and the warmth of being loved by someone. It is impossible for invulnerability and intimacy to exist in the same space. There will be hurt and rejection when you seek love, but the heart is a resilient muscle. With every ache, it grows stronger than it was before. If, on other hand, we choose not to be vulnerable and withhold putting our heart out there because we fear that it might get hurt, then we lose not only the opportunity to find new love but also the ability to grow.

Love takes time to deepen. It is a process that develops over years, attaining maturity much like a bottle of wine. If we are constantly strutting around with dissatisfaction and looking for the next best thing, then there won’t be sufficient time for any feelings to develop. The only place a flawless and perfect relationship can exist is within the peripheries of your mind. Know that real love requires compromise. Everyone has a set of attributes they look for in a potential partner, and that is completely understandable. However, when those traits run as long as your grocery list, then you're bound to be disappointed in your search for relationships. Have some fundamental qualities that you look for in a partner, in practical terms not more than four or five. In my own life, I value someone who is attractive to me physically, engages in some kind of spiritual self-inquiry, and someone playful that I can share laughs with. If they satisfy those three fundamental qualities that I'm seeking, then I'm willing to accept or work with aspects of their personality that do not fit mine exactly.

Another way to attract more love into your world is by exploring various opportunities to meet people in your life. Are you someone that enjoys reading and discussing books? Then seek out book clubs in your neighborhood. Do you feel motivated about a particular cause? Find volunteer programs that help you dedicate your time to something you'd like to do while also enabling you to be in the vicinity of people with common goals or interests. Join an activity that requires a partner, like salsa dancing, rock climbing, or acro-yoga. Nothing builds connections better than indulging in an activity together. Attracting new love can even be as simple as talking to more people. Start conversations with strangers, and connect with people in your everyday life. Who knows? That person ahead of you in the coffee line could be the partner you've always wanted.

In the end, the love you find won't be sustained if you are not willing to submit to it. Love never conquers, love submits. This is not the same as letting someone take advantage of you. It means that when you love someone, you do not always try to maintain the upper hand in the relationship. There are no winners and losers here. In practical terms, this means you agree not to influence your partner out of fear, jealousy, or other insecurities. At the same time, change your own behaviors that are sabotaging yourself and the relationship. Understand that to love is to maximize your own growth alongside the other; it is not about boosting your ego at the expense of another.

One last barrier to love is not having enough patience. We may have everything going right for us. We might be attractive and emotionally competent. We might also possess a thriving career and numerous outlets to meet people. Yet, the kind of love that we are looking for may be eluding us. It is easy to lose heart at this point, but it also helps us to appreciate how special it is when the right person walks into our lives. We have to recognize that it is not entirely in our hands to meet someone that we would want to fall in love with. Chance has a big role to play. The best strategy would be to eliminate our love-barriers by accepting ourselves, becoming attractive both on the inside and outside, maturing emotionally, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ckqO2zjL5Wk">waiting for love to find us in the end</a>.
<h5>Credits</h5>
<ul>
	<li>Background image for Rumi's quote  - <a href="http://carlbert.deviantart.com/art/dark-blue-texture-267451994">http://carlbert.deviantart.com/art/dark-blue-texture-267451994</a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>114</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-11-02 23:22:15]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-11-02 23:22:15]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[barriers-to-love]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Seeking Refuge in the Now</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/refuge-in-the-now/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 23:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=127</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-128" src="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/mountain_milky_way_edit-1024x710.jpg" alt="What is true in this moment?" width="1024" height="710" />

It is almost sunset. A warm wind blows over my bald head as I run barefoot on the shore of this nearly empty tropical beach. Accompanying me is my faithful golden retriever. Though she's a little old, at least in dog years, she still has the energy of a puppy. We play with each other the way animals do when they are happy, blurring the line between man and beast. I am not far from my home; it is right on the beach. I look up to see my wife making dinner. She's a very creative person and the kitchen is definitely one of the places that fosters her creativity. As the smell of the food wafts in the air, I glance at her through the kitchen window and see how lucky I am to have the life that I've always wanted. And right then I snap out of my daydream very abruptly. At the moment, I am nowhere near the water. In fact, I am standing in my kitchen, chopping a bell pepper, getting ready to make my breakfast for the day. The same breakfast that I make every day.

I've been a dreamer all of my life. Moving between fantasy and reality happens constantly without requiring any effort from myself. My default mode is to drift away into an idyllic future or sometimes, when my anxiety runs high, into a dreadful one. What doesn't help is the depersonalization that I sometimes experience that merges both my worlds together and often in unpleasant ways.

The experts say that a wandering mind is an unhappy mind<sup>[1]</sup>. If that is the case then I probably am not a very happy person. I wouldn't particularly categorize myself as someone like that, but what I do know is that the times I've experienced most happiness is when I've been wholly consumed by the present moment. The only moment as some would say. This usually happens when I'm writing, making music, working out with weights in the gym or rock climbing. The times when I'm wrestling with a technical engineering challenge at work is definitely one of those rare moments where I lose sense of my worries and troubles. I am seized by the moment, as the girl in the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QcKOYLmr5TE">final few seconds of the movie Boyhood</a> says. That feeling stays with me, but not for long. It's got a very short half life. And before you know it, I am back to daydreaming about living a simple life elsewhere with my imagined partner, or something like that.

Whenever I drift away into to a delightful fantasy, I come out of it and start comparing how I am here and not there. The times when I feel particularly sad or fearful, my mind wanders to the future and makes it look bleak and miserable. Something in me is unable to be with where I am in the present. I either escape into a comforting fantasy or extrapolate my present difficulties into the future.

The hardest part about the human condition is the fact that the present moment is always eluding us, save for a few brief seconds here and there. A few days ago, a friend and I were having a conversation in a cozy hot tub on a chilly San Franciscan night. I told her how frustrated I was feeling with my current state of being. The reasons being plenty, but the few principals among them being the lack of meaning in my day job, the way the current immigration laws feel stifling to me and the lack of an intimate partner weighing in on me while I age slowly. There was a palpable sadness in my tone and an urge to confide these feelings with someone. After attentively listening to me, my friend, <a href="http://artemisiashine.com/">who is a very wise counselor</a>, informed me that she can clearly see a pattern in my thinking. I just can't seem to be able to hold the sadness and let it hang in there without stretching it into the future. According to my thinking, since I haven't figured out yet how to turn my passion for helping others into a livelihood, my future self will also be afflicted with the same problem. If an intimate partnership seems lacking at the moment, then I am reminded that I am only getting older and my fantasy is incomplete without the company of a loving, attractive, playful partner. Whenever things are hard in any given moment, it is my tendency to fear that those hardships will stay with me in the future. The present, if it's difficult, colors my future gray. When the future seems colorful, the present by comparison appears monochromatic. This mode of thinking strips the intensity and value of the moment we are in right now.

There is always a silent comparison going on between my current self and the future or past version of me. I look back to my childhood and see how careless it was without worries and I look at my ideal future self only to feel frustrated because I don't have a clear path to that future. In both these cases, there's always something lacking right now. Something I once had has been lost or there is something in the future that I haven't attained yet. In this way of being, the present moment is experienced as nothing but an unsatisfying conduit between a pleasant past and a blissful future.

After I finished sharing my story with my friend and let the heat of the water in the hot tub soak into me, I felt some relief. Did she solve my problems? No. Did I end up having an epiphany about how to fix them? Not really. All I did was to make room for my frustration to come up and transpire. But I gained some insight that night. I am discovering that when the sadness or frustration visits me again, I don't have to heed the stories that my mind comes up with in those moments but, instead, I just need to let the present moment contain whatever that is showing up. Part of my re-training is to see the now as the only truth that I can hold on to. Whenever I experience a difficult feeling, be it sadness or fear, and my mind starts to wander, I have to remind myself to ask this one question - <strong>in this moment, what is true?</strong> By asking this, I can learn to see that what is showing up is only valid for this moment. By taking this approach, I can go beyond the stories my mind conjures up and seek to experience the underlying feeling without the mental chatter surrounding it. We rarely get to experience the underlying feeling without the mind's constant analysis and judgment about that feeling. When some sadness hovers over me, the question "What is true in this moment?" helps me to see that only the experience of the sadness is true, the thoughts that come up about a dismal future don't have any validity behind them. When I'm possessed by anxiety, this question often helps me cuts through the fallacies about my future that are conjured up by my agitated mind. In this way, I am learning to completely submit to the present moment, if not all the time, at least when a difficult emotion bubbles up. I am letting the present moment contain me and all of my feelings. I am learning to seek refuge in the now.
<h5>Footnotes</h5>
<ol>
	<li>"A Wandering Mind is an Unhappy One" - <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-wandering-mind-is-an-un/">http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-wandering-mind-is-an-un/</a></li>
</ol>
<h5>Credits</h5>
<ol>
	<li>Background image for quote - <a href="https://flic.kr/p/qnU2Ci">https://flic.kr/p/qnU2Ci</a></li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>127</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-11-12 23:56:34]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-11-12 23:56:34]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[refuge-in-the-now]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_slug]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[seeking-refuge-in-the-now]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Here&#039;s Why You Are Not Successful (Yet)</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/redefine-success-metrics/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 03:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=137</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="size-large wp-image-138" src="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/success_metric-1024x683.jpg" alt="May be your failure is a result of choosing the wrong metric to measure your success" width="1024" height="683" />

Like most people, I have a desire to be physically attractive. I also want to be strong and fit, but the looking good part is definitely a big motivator for me to go to the gym. Every Monday morning, I wake up and weigh myself right after taking a shower. This way, not only is the measurement more or less consistent every week, but it keeps my eating and drinking within healthy limits over the weekend. If you plotted the weight I gained every week on a graph, you'll see somewhat of a linear upwards progression. I found this quite unsettling. What was I doing wrong here? I lift weights twice a week and on two other days I row for 25 minutes along with 10 minutes of core exercises. If I can find a climbing partner, I also throw some rock climbing into the mix as well. However, still, come Monday morning, the scale always betrays me. This started to bother me and I felt unsuccessful in my journey to becoming a stronger and sexier version of myself, well, at least the sexy part of it. Then, in one big whoosh, I knew what I was doing wrong. I was obsessing over the results of a process while my effort was directed towards something else. In my case, I was concerned about the weight I was gaining without restricting my food intake, but my efforts were directed towards lifting heavier weights. This is definitely bound to make me unhappy, since without proper calorie restriction, I am bound to increase my body weight. Instead, if I chose to focus on the increase or decrease in the weights I lifted, then that'd have given me a more accurate measure of my progress in my fitness regimen. When I do that, I can see that because of my consistent weightlifting practice I have managed to gradually increase the numbers on all the major lifts in my workout. What I realized is that we sometimes tend to choose the wrong metric to measure our success in an aspect of our life.
<h3><strong>Choose the Right Metric</strong></h3>
A lot of us measure ourselves based on a wide variety of metrics that have no right to be there in the first place. We ask ourselves how much weight we have lost or how much money we made over the course of a month, yet we might have done nothing to change our status quo in those specific areas. What am I trying to say here? I propose that we only measure something that we are directly trying to influence or change. Don't measure something yourself unless you've exerted some effort to change that part of your life. Unless you are restricting your daily calories, it doesn't make sense to measure your weight loss. If you did, you will only end up failing. If you try to measure how much money you saved while you are busy spending money on getting the latest gadgets, then you are definitely bound for disappointment. Ask yourself if your actions in any way justify your type of measurement. This sounds trivial, but it has really helped me not to worry about metrics that I'm not currently trying to improve.
<h3><strong>Don't Use Metrics That are Beyond Your Control</strong></h3>
Most things in life cannot be quantified and are beyond our control, yet more often than not, we obsess over those metrics. For example, sometimes I worry that I am not a successful writer because my articles are not widely shared on social media. By that metric, I am nothing more than a failure. But I refuse to see it that way. My measure of success as a budding writer is simple: Can I write and publish an article every 1 to 2 weeks? If I can do that, then I've been successful in that period of two weeks. The ability for my article to penetrate every corner of social media is simply beyond my control. Granted, I can post it to this blog's <a href="https://www.facebook.com/acoachcalledlife/">Facebook page</a> or share it on Reddit, but beyond that, I don’t have any control over whether other people would think my article is worthy of sharing or not. In the same way, in the past I used to think that I was not a successful musician because none of my songs ever reached a large audience. However, now, my metric of success is whether I can put in 1 to 2 hours a week to practice and compose music.
<h3><strong>How to Be Successful</strong></h3>
To be successful, we have two choices available. We can either apply effort to improve our set of chosen metrics or we can redefine our metrics of success to correspond with where our effort is currently in place. In my example, this means that as long as the weights that I lift are gradually getting heavier, I’m successful in my fitness routine. I can’t try to increase my lifts while at the same time attempt to decrease my body weight. The former requires an increase in food intake, while the latter requires restriction of calories. If what I want is to lose weight, then I'd have to redefine my metric of success and take action accordingly. In this case that means consuming fewer calories.

Choose metrics that are attainable with the right effort and those which are not vague. Instead of saying, "I want my project to be wildly successful", which can be beyond your control, choose to frame your metric as something more measurable than that, like whether or not you were able to spend certain hours on that project in a week. If you are working on your social skills, it might be harder to be successful if you want to be liked by everybody; however, if you can just tell yourself that you are going to talk to five strangers every day regardless of their opinion about you, then that might be easier for you to accomplish.

This is not a trick to make you always win. You can do this and still fail. You may want to become a writer, but can be unsuccessful in writing over a thousand words a week because you had other priorities in life. But your failure will be due to your lack of discipline or lack of effort, rather than something external and beyond yourself.

Some people work really hard but are always dissatisfied with the results. I hope these words help them to reassess their metrics for success and channel their efforts toward more achievable goals.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>137</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-11-26 03:48:16]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-11-26 03:48:16]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[redefine-success-metrics]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Rough Guide to Getting Better at Conversations</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/getting-better-at-conversations/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 23:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=145</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Good conversation is something we all crave. Look at any dating website and you'll know what I'm talking about. Being able to hold a deep meaningful conversation is something almost everyone looks for in a potential partner. But what makes a conversation good or interesting? To me, a good conversation is like a good meal. It leaves me completely satisfied after I have one while at the same time I'm looking forward to more. As with any well-prepared dish, there are several key ingredients that make a conversation enjoyable. Here is how you cook up an interesting conversation.

<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-148" src="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/steak_dinner1.jpg" alt="Meaty meal" width="1728" height="1152" />
<h3>Make it Meaty</h3>
A good meal should have something substantial as its foundation. Let's take a sirloin steak for example (sorry vegans/vegetarians, I couldn't find a better metaphor). What makes it that good? The meat, of course. That is at the heart of this food. In the same way, how do you add weight to your conversation? By bringing emotions into it. For that to happen, you can't just hang out at the surface level of a conversation, you have to dig in a little deeper. By engaging the other person to talk about their passions and interests, you are able to rev up their emotional engine. On the other hand, when you talk to someone without making any room for emotions, then they are going to get bored easily.

The reason a lot of conversation remains at surface level is because we are afraid of exploring beyond our safe limits. But without taking risks, we risk losing a deeper connection. A hearty meal is enjoyed thoroughly, with all of its layers. Similarly, there are several layers to a conversation and the deeper you go, the more flavorful and juicy it can get.

To begin with, simply start light. Rather than jumping into something serious right away, ask a few innocuous questions to get the conversation flowing. This is akin to heating the pan before throwing the steak onto it. Once your conversation pan is hot enough, start to indulge something more substantial. This can be achieved by discussing topics that are sure to fire up the emotional engines of your parties. These topics include dreams, aspirations, current challenges in careers and personal life, goals, things that make someone feel joyous, issues they are angry about, loss, fears, first time experiences, family, travel adventures, etc. They don't have to be personal all the time. If there is a shared interest, then talking about philosophy, outer space, gun control or your even local sports team’s disastrous defeat can become a good focal point to converse about. But when discussing anything non-personal, be careful not to just thrown in facts and figures at someone. Make sure to notice the emotion behind those facts and try to bring them forward. Don't turn it into a competition of who knows more than the other. A delightful meal is never a pie eating contest. A conversation is not necessarily a debate. Instead of competing, make it a point to understand your conversational partner first.
<h3>Use Condiments But With Caution.</h3>
Think of the last gratifying meal you had. Chances are, it not only had something substantial underlying it but also had some seasoning added to it. Now think about a good conversation you enjoyed in the past; chances are, it was filled with humor, laughter, eye contact, storytelling, physical touch, and gesticulation. A steak by itself is hard to relish. Even if it's cooked well, without proper seasoning, it tastes bland. A conversation is subject to the same rules. Season your conversation with some humor and gestures. Emote your words. Use eye contact to ground yourself and the other person. Touch now and then; this goes for a conversation only involving men too. A handshake, high five, fist bump and hugs are all good examples of physical touch.

Experiment with different seasonings from your conversational pantry. But be aware of the danger of over seasoning. If you are only interested in making jokes with the hope of impressing the other person, then they are not going to feel the connection. It doesn't make any sense to eat just the condiments without the meat. It can become cloying really soon.
<h3>Offer a Little Bit More</h3>
A well-prepared meal offers a lot more than the modicum. There are many side dishes and lots of attention to detail. A good conversation is similar; there's a lot more talked about than the bare minimum necessary to get one's point across. One easy trick to expand your conversation is to add more details. For example, when someone at work asks you how your weekend was, instead of saying "Great," you could let them know what it was about it that made it great for you. Or if your weekend was just OK, what could have made it better? Cook up some sides; throw in a few different sauces to enhance your conversational meal. Give the other person the option of digging in for more. When they see you expanding your side of the discussion and not just answering yes or no, they feel compelled to share a story of their own.
<h3>Savor The Conversation</h3>
It doesn't make any sense to go to an expensive restaurant and just stuff your mouth with their most highly priced item on the menu and then rush back home. Just as you would savor a nicely prepared meal, you should also try to savor the conversation. It is imperative that you hear the other person out completely before responding. Let their words hit you and your imagination. Let each word reach your senses as you try to build a picture of what they are talking about. Taste the different flavors of the sentences and their meaning. In our fast food culture, this is a quality that needs learning. Be sure to practice active listening.

Don't be in a hurry to say something back, even if you have the perfect joke lined up. One of the simplest hacks I'm trying to implement these days comes from the following quote by <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Just-One-Thing-Developing-Practice/dp/1608820319">Rick Hanson, in his book, Just One Thing</a>.
<blockquote>“After someone finishes speaking to you, take a little longer than usual before you reply. Let the weight of the other person’s words—and more importantly, the person’s underlying wants and feelings—really sink in. Notice how this pause affects you—and affects the other person’s response to you.”</blockquote>
Some of us can't wait to say something witty or something to the contrary or anything to fill in the gaps and keep the conversation going. We don't eat like that, so stop trying to stuff yourself and the other person with words without giving an opportunity to be captured by what just transpired. Remember, a multi-course meal consists of breaks and pauses. Slow down your pace of talking and slow down your response. The other person will pick up on this and feel your calm.
<h3>Bring on The Wine</h3>
<img class="alignright wp-image-154" src="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/wine.jpg" alt="Wine" width="376" height="282" />I mean this one literally. A lot of good food is often paired with wine and other alcohol. Though I'm not a huge drinker myself (those days are long over; goodbye early 20s), I find that alcohol does help people lower their inhibitions and helps them say what's on their mind. But, it comes with a warning. It must not be used as a crutch all the time. If your conversations always happen in the vicinity of a drink, then try and experiment with engaging in meaningful discussions without relying on any social lubricant.

A conversation is a shared meal. Take turns talking, ask each other questions, dig a little deeper, add details, sprinkle some humor, welcome silences and natural breaks and most importantly, savor the meal together.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>145</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-12-17 23:44:14]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-12-17 23:44:14]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[getting-better-at-conversations]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Do This The Next Time You Are Feeling Anxious</title>
		<link>http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=161</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[swamy_g]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acoachcalledlife.com/?p=161</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-163" src="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/boxing_hit.jpg" alt="fighting with your anxiety" width="1952" height="1602" />

We are so used to the language of war. We fight cancer, talk about our battle with depression, or try to overcome anxiety when it feels overwhelming. Mainstream thinking is that anything that is causing unease must be fought and conquered. But when such strategies are aimed towards psychiatric disorders, they are futile at best, and at worst, it prolongs the duration of its associated symptoms.

How can anyone win a fight where the mere act of fighting increases your chances of losing? You might have realized this in dealing with your own anxiety. The more we put up a fight and resist those unpleasant feelings, the more intense they become. When we turn our backs and run away from it, the worse the anxiety gets. What I'm about to suggest to you in the following paragraphs might sound diametrically opposite from what your instincts tell you to do in the face of a threat. Before you let your defenses stop you from reading the rest of the article, I suggest you tell yourself that you'd get through it regardless of what your kicking and screaming mind tells you.

[caption id="attachment_170" align="aligncenter" width="1024"]<img class="wp-image-170 size-large" src="http://acoachcalledlife.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/stop_fight_anxiety_white_2000x2000-1024x974.jpg" alt="Stop the senseless fight against your own body and mind" width="1024" height="974" /> <em>Stop the senseless fight against your own body and mind</em>[/caption]
<h3>Give Up</h3>
That's right, the best defense against anxiety is not an offense; it is none at all. Surrender to your anxiety. Throw in the towel, throw up your hands and yell, "I quit fighting. I give up!” Giving up the fight with anxiety is the first step towards recovering. We waste a considerable amount of energy (both mental and physical) attacking anxiety and it doesn't have to be this way. When you give up the fighting, you also give up the suffering. This is the key realization that got me closer to breaking free from the confines of anxiety. Once you give up the struggle, there is a lot more room for you to stretch. You go where your anxiety takes you without throwing tantrums or resisting.

We are not hardwired to react this way to something we perceive as a threat. This goes against our instinct of either gearing up for combat or running away when faced with an apparent danger. This might have helped our great ancestors survive the dangerous African plains, rife with predatory animals but when the same strategy is applied to problems inside ourselves, it fails profoundly. With anxiety, you sometimes have to do the opposite of what fear is telling you to do. Surrendering to anxious feelings is not very easy. An underlying belief that makes this possible for me is the fact that anxiety is harmless. It cannot damage me physically. I am not going to die from it or go insane, even though that is exactly what my fearful mind tells me in the midst of high anxiety.
<h3>Why It Makes Sense to Surrender</h3>
Your anxiety is a result of a high level of stress in your life. When this happens, there's a part of your nervous system called the Sympathetic Nervous System (SNS) that kicks into action. Whether this stress is physical, like a grizzly bear chasing you down, or psychological, as in you're stuck in a job that you highly dislike, then your body produces certain stress hormones; namely adrenaline (short-acting stress hormone) and cortisol (which takes a lot longer to be secreted but remains in our system for an extended period of time). The effects of these hormones are usually felt as racing heart, sweaty palms, dizziness, and other tell-tale signs of anxiety. Anxiety cannot be completely reduced as a result of stress chemicals in the body; it has an existential and spiritual component to it, but for the sake of this article I'm keeping it simple.

After the stressor in a situation has been removed, the Parasympathetic Nervous System (PSNS) kicks in which has the opposite effect of the SNS. It relaxes your muscles, lowers your heart rate, and puts the body into a more restful state. When you are under a high level of psychological stress, the stress hormones released make you feel anxious. When you fight those feelings, it puts an additional stress on your system which makes you feel even more anxious. This stress-anxiety cycle can only be broken by engaging the PSNS. By surrendering to the feelings of anxiety, you send a message to your brain telling it that there is no harm in this moment. You give full permission for the anxious feelings to persist thereby negating any threat. When you do that, the body and the mind can relax and that can be the key to breaking that vicious cycle.

When you experience an acid burn, you have to neutralize it with a base. When we resist the feelings of anxiety, it is akin to adding more acid on top of your burn. By moving towards your anxiety instead of running away from it, you neutralize the situation.
<h3>You Are Not a Coward</h3>
In modern times, with its insistence on always being a winner, the word 'surrender' has become synonymous with cowardice. If you are already feeling ashamed of your anxiety, then telling you to give up and surrender to it would seem even more hurtful to your ego. But this is an act of bravery. To move towards your fears without your protective shield is a prime example of courageousness. Hollywood tells us that we are heroes only if we slay the dragon, or conquer our nemesis. If the relationship between you and anxiety is that of a warrior and a nemesis, then be prepared to fight for a long time to come. We cannot confront fear with resistance; only acceptance can extinguish that fire. Anxiety is the excitation of your nervous system; fighting it only produces more excitation. Giving up and floating through the anxiety calms down and rebalances your nervous system.
<h3>Having a Word With Your Anxiety</h3>
Next time your anxiety is running high, imagine it as a person (and not a scary monster) and talk to it. To make it simple and easy, I've included a short script:
<blockquote>"Hello, anxiety, my old friend. I've come to talk with you again. But today is different. Today I am not going to resist the way you make me feel. I am defenseless right now and I give you full permission to do whatever you desire with me. You are free to make me feel nauseous, light headed, churn and upset my stomach, constrict my chest, make me feel unreal, and cause a high degree of fear in me. I am open and completely accepting of the sensations, thoughts, emotions, and feelings that you produce. You are welcome to stay as long as you want."

&nbsp;</blockquote>
Whenever I repeat these words to myself in the midst of a strong current of anxiety, I feel as if more space has opened up inside me and I start to feel lighter. However, the anxiety will not magically disappear right away. This is not a magic mantra to instantly dissolve anxiety. It is not some reverse psychological trick to rid yourself of fear. You will still feel all the symptoms of anxiety, especially if you have been fighting it for years. But slowly, over time, after being open to these feelings, you'll start to notice that the intensity of these feelings gradually reduces. You will feel the uneasiness, but you won't suffer unnecessarily. This approach reduces your hypervigilance towards anxiety and you start to worry less every day. Your level of caring and pre-planning for your next encounter with anxiety decreases dramatically. This frees you up mentally and emotionally giving you the much needed time to take up long-forgotten activities of interest. Indulging in those can also help you forget about your worries and connect more with life. Wouldn't you want that?]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>161</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-12-18 19:01:37]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[0000-00-00 00:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[what-to-do-when-feeling-anxious]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
